Welcome back. In the next few concepts,
欢迎回来 在下面的几个页面中
we will walk through critical steps for localizing
我们会实现一个粒子滤波器
our car by implementing a particle filter.
在这个过程中 了解车辆定位的几个关键步骤
Our ultimate goal is determine how well each of
我们的最终目标 是确定每个粒子位置
our particle positions represents the actual position of our car.
在表述车辆实际位置方面的准确性
To do this, we must use car sensor and map inputs to weigh each particle.
要做到这一点 我们必须使用车辆传感器和地图输入为每个粒子赋权
In the next few concepts,
在下面的几个页面里
we will walk through this process for a single particle by
我们会把车辆传感器的地标观察数据
transforming car sensor landmark observations from the car coordinate system,
从车辆坐标系统转换为地图坐标系统
to the map coordinate system,
把转换后的观察结果和地图上最近的地标相关联
associating these transformed observations with the nearest landmark on the map.
从而了解单个粒子的这一过程
Updating our particle weight by applying
首先为每个测量值应用
the multivariate Gaussian probability density function for each measurement,
多变量的高斯概率密度函数 更新粒子权重
then combining the probabilities of all the measurements by taking their product.
然后计算所有测量值的概率 相乘得到合并概率
This final weight is our posterior probability.
最终权重是我们的后验概率
In this video, we will go over the first step,
在本视频中 我们会学习第一步
transforming observations to map coordinates.
把观察数据转换为地图坐标
This figure here depicts a car observing three nearby landmarks,
这里的图描述了一辆车观察到三个附近地标
L5, L1, and L2.
L5、L1 和 L2
The car sees them as observation one,
车辆将其视作观察 1
observation two, and observation three.
观察 2、以及观察 3
Remember that by convention,
记住 按照惯例
we define the car's coordinates such as X is
我们定义车辆坐标时 X 指向
pointed in the direction of the vehicle's heading with
车辆的航向
y rotated plus 90 degrees or to the left perpendicular as depicted here.
Y 垂直于 X 指向车辆的左方
The blue box in this figure represents a particle whose weight we want to update.
图中的蓝色方框代表一个粒子 我们需要更新它的权重
To do this, we will transform the car observations to map coordinates.
要做到这一点 我们要把车辆的观察数据转换为地图坐标
We can achieve this transformation by passing our data through
转换时 我们通过一个绘制车辆地图坐标的三角函数
a trigonometric function that maps car coordinates, to map coordinates.
把数据传递到地图坐标上
This function is called a homogeneous transformation,
这个函数叫做齐次变换
and is composed of a rotation in a translation.
它由一次平移中的一次旋转组成
Essentially, we all need to rotate the maps frame to match the particles point of view.
本质上来说 我们需要旋转地图画面 来匹配粒子视角
Then we will move the origin of the frame to the location of the particle.
然后 我们把画面的圆点移动到粒子位置
We can do both of these steps in one matrix multiplication,
我们可以使用齐次变换
using the homogeneous transformation.
通过一次性的矩阵乘法完成这两步操作
We know that our particle has a heading of
我们知道 粒子的航向为
negative 90 degrees and a map location of four come of five.
负 90 度 地图位置为 (4,5)
We can visualize this process by drawing a coordinate frame at the map origin,
我们可以在地图原点绘制一个坐标系 可视化这个操作
then determining the location of the particle frame in the map coordinate system.
然后在地图坐标系中确定粒子位置
To get to the particles frame from the mass point of view,
要从数学视角达到粒子位置
we first have to rotate by negative 90 degrees like so,
我们首先需要旋转负 90 度 就象这样
then we'll move to the particles position by
然后移动到粒子位置 具体方法是
passing our observation coordinates XC and YC,
传递观察坐标 Xc 和 Yc
our particle coordinates XP and YP and a rotation angle theta of negative 90 degrees.
粒子坐标 Xp 和 Yp、以及负 90 度的旋转角度 θ
This homogeneous transformation right here does exactly what we just did.
就是这里的这个齐次变换
This formulation with the extra one as a third row is known as homogeneous coordinates.
这里的这个公式 加上下面额外的第三行 被叫做齐次坐标
More detail can be found in the instructor notes.
你可以在讲师注释中发现更多详情
Let's quickly break down this homogeneous transformation here.
我们迅速分解这个齐次变换
The two by two matrix in the top left represents the rotation component about the Z axis.
左上角的 2 乘 2 矩阵代表围绕 Z 轴的旋转分量
Remember that we're only doing this in 2D right now.
记住 我们现在是在二维平面操作
The third column here represents the translation component.
这里的第三栏代表平移分量
We complete the transformation by multiplying
要完成变换 我们需要遍历车辆坐标
through by the observation in car coordinates.
的乘法操作
To summarize, this homogeneous transformation is a transformation
总结一下 这个齐次变换是从车辆坐标变换为
from car coordinates to map coordinates in the maps frame.
地图坐标系中的地图坐标
Using our observations in the car
使用车辆坐标系统中的观察数据
coordinate system and our particle pose in the map system,
以及地图系统中的粒子位置
we have everything we need to transform observations into map coordinates,
我们就可以把观察数据转换为地图坐标
and ultimately determine the final weight of our particle. Good luck.
并最终确定粒子的权重 祝你好运！